<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ahmed Space</title>
    <link>https://ahmedspace.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ahmed Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ahmedspace.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to recover a corrupted flash memory using F3 tools under Linux</title>
      <link>https://ahmedspace.com/how-to-recover-a-corrupted-flash-memory-using-f3-tools-under-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahmedspace.com/how-to-recover-a-corrupted-flash-memory-using-f3-tools-under-linux/</guid>
      <description>Note: This tutorial requires Linux. If you want to test your flash under windows check out: test-and-detect-fake-flash-with-h2testw
So you have a corrupted flash memory, you copy files into it and when you try to open it later, they don&amp;rsquo;t work. There are number of reasons for this problem, one of them is aging, flash memories have a lifetime too and there is a limited number of writes. If this was the cause of the problem, then it is time to retire it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic Case Insensitive In Database Systems: How To Solve Alef With and Without Hamza Problem</title>
      <link>https://ahmedspace.com/arabic-case-insensitive-in-database-systems-how-to-solve-alef-with-and-without-hamza-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 16:35:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ahmedspace.com/arabic-case-insensitive-in-database-systems-how-to-solve-alef-with-and-without-hamza-problem/</guid>
      <description>When I first started learning database systems, I ran into problems dealing with Arabic text in databases. Since these problems were specific to the Arabic language, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t easily find solutions on the internet. I try in this post to summarize the solutions I know to a common Arabic text problem in database systems, hoping it will help someone struggling to deal with Arabic text in databases.
You have characters which are considered the same in Arabic (like Alef &#39;ุง&#39; and Alef without Hamza &#39;ุฃ&#39;), but these are two different characters in database systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>